butlercc.edu 2013-12-04

# Privacy Statement

Privacy Statement
This privacy statement applies to this Web site and certain other linked Web sites on servers
owned and operated by Butler Community College. The privacy statement discloses our
information gathering and dissemination practices for all Butler Community College Web sites.
IP Address and Authentication
We log all connections to our Web servers. Those log files include your IP address. An IP
address is NOT personally identifiable information, but general information about your location,
your connection to the Internet, and the Internet Service Provider that is being used. We use your
IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer the Web sites.
However, when you connect to any of our systems through the use of individual or pooled
modems, wireless connections on our campuses, or residence halls' connections we ask you to
authenticate using a user identification and password. We do this so that these resources are used
only by authorized students, staff, and faculty of this institution. In this case the log files do
provide personally identifiable information. This information includes a history of the Web sites
and pages that you visit.
Finally, for many of our specialized services, such as our e-mail systems, Canvas, or the Pipeline
Portal System, your authentication allows us to provide you with specific information about your
classes, grades, and financial status. These activities are also logged by us and include a history
of the Web sites and pages that you visit.
In summary, on our sites we normally track only non-personal information but when you enter a
user ID and password we log what you are doing while using our services. (This is one of the
reasons you should never give anyone your user ID and password.)
Cookies
"Cookies" are small pieces of information stored in a user's browser that give that user a unique
identification. If you are attempting to access our restricted content, we will use cookies for
authentication purposes only. All cookies are established on a per session basis, and are not
stored permanently on your computer.
Personal Information
Butler Community College may collect personal information through various forms, surveys, or
applications to allow us to contact you, improve our services, or create, complete, or update
information about your records with Butler Community College. Information obtained via
contact forms are only used for the defined purpose of contact and necessary college records.
The user may be contacted through telephone, mail, or e-mail in response to the request being
made.

Any personal information collected that pertains to financial aid is shared with specific third
party loan agencies for the sole purpose of servicing student loans for Butler Community
College.
By using our Web sites, you represent that you are not less than 13 years of age. Personal
information that is collected is treated as though it was submitted by an adult.
We do not sell or rent your contact information to third parties. However, we do provide this
when we are required to disclose such information by law or in response to a request from a law
enforcement agency or authority.
Butler Community College is not responsible for personal information that is disclosed by users
posting to discussion boards in Canvas. All users of Canvas are to exercise caution when
disclosing personal information. Any information disclosed should be for educational purposes
only.
Except with regard to any contact information you may provide us via the Web sites, all
comments, feedback, information, or materials submitted to Butler Community College or in
association with our Web sites will be considered non-confidential and the property of Butler
Community College.
Security
Butler Community College Web sites have security measures in place to protect against the loss,
misuse and alteration of the information under our control; however, Butler Community College
does not guarantee the performance or adequacy of such security measures.
Links to Other Web Sites
The Web sites contain links to other Web sites that are not owned or operated by Butler
Community College. The College is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third
parties or the content or security of such Web sites.
Dissemination of Information
Butler Community College staff uses both personally identifiable information and non-
personally identifiable information to aid them in diagnosing network and server issues and in
planning for capacity and performance issues. Personally identifiable information is also used in
diagnosing and attempting to solve problems of particular users at their request.
Butler Community College staff also uses personally identifiable information to aid in any
investigation of unauthorized, inappropriate, illegal, or irresponsible use of computing resources.
This information may be used internally to disable or remove accounts. Butler Community
College will also cooperate with external agencies when required to disclose such information by
law or in response to a request from a law enforcement agency or authority.

Butler Community College will not sell, rent, or otherwise disseminate information that it
collects on its Web sites to other parties except as required by law and for financial aid purposes.
Butler Community College may make changes to this privacy statement. Changes will be posted
to this statement so that users are always aware items concerning their privacy.
